<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>3D Genomics | </title>
    <link>https://yezhengSTAT.github.io/tag/3d-genomics/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://yezhengSTAT.github.io/tag/3d-genomics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>3D Genomics</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 31 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://yezhengSTAT.github.io/media/icon_hu73f7157ab925ae64d73c94fd5ceef54d_49900_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>3D Genomics</title>
      <link>https://yezhengSTAT.github.io/tag/3d-genomics/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>3D Chromatin Organization</title>
      <link>https://yezhengSTAT.github.io/project/3dgenome/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://yezhengSTAT.github.io/project/3dgenome/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;project-introduction&#34;&gt;Project Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The role that chromatin architecture plays in the mechanism of gene regulation has undergone a dramatic transformation with the emergence of Hi-C and other 3C-derived high throughput technology for interrogating the three-dimensional configurations of the genome and identifying regions that are in close spatial proximity in a genome-wide fashion. As the sequencing depth grows, the resolution to investigate the 3D chromatin interactions goes from Megabase scale to kilobase or even hundred-base genomic scale. Furthermore, with the development of other &amp;ldquo;C&amp;rdquo;-related techniques, for instance, HiChIP, DNaseHiC, Capture Hi-C, etc., we will be able to investigate all kinds of genomic interactions at ultra-high resolution across the whole genome from the anchor regions that can be associated with clinically relevant loci such as regulatory elements, single nucleotide polymorphisms (SNPs) from GWAS studies, chromatin domain boundaries or promoters. Analysis of 3D genome data will resolve many fundamental and long-standing questions involving the mechanism of gene regulation from distal non-coding regulatory variants, linking novel SNPs to putative disease-associated genes related to all sorts of disorders, the connection between chromatin domain structure variation and cancer or other genetic diseases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Such technological advances in 3D genomics lead to great needs for new statistical models and computational tools to harness the embedding conformation information present in Hi-C data. To achieve decent interaction resolution, namely, how specific the region can be if we zoom in the genome to the largest extent, one study usually has billions of reads for each biological replicate. Hence, it poses a tough challenge on the model which should be theoretically sound and practically applicable and implementable within a short time. Realizing the demand in the field, I have developed a few fundamental methods, mHi-C, FreeHi-C, FreeHi-C SpikeIn, BandNorm and scVI-3D, with the corresponding software packages or pipelines to address many basic needs in dealing with Hi-C data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;















&lt;figure  &gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;te&#34; srcset=&#34;
               /project/3dgenome/multi-reads_hu95b880fb2c81768720415bef0200f400_1627683_472aeb3f2eedb0e149c66981559d59b7.webp 400w,
               /project/3dgenome/multi-reads_hu95b880fb2c81768720415bef0200f400_1627683_9c5860f2399ff831e1ad93ebe6075cad.webp 760w,
               /project/3dgenome/multi-reads_hu95b880fb2c81768720415bef0200f400_1627683_1200x1200_fit_q100_h2_lanczos_3.webp 1200w&#34;
               src=&#34;https://yezhengSTAT.github.io/project/3dgenome/multi-reads_hu95b880fb2c81768720415bef0200f400_1627683_472aeb3f2eedb0e149c66981559d59b7.webp&#34;
               width=&#34;747&#34;
               height=&#34;760&#34;
               loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Due to the importance of sequencing depth in Hi-C analysis, I developed mHi-C (Zheng et al. 2019 &lt;em&gt;eLife&lt;/em&gt;) to utilize multi-mapping reads that are discarded in Hi-C benchmark analysis pipeline. Multi-mapping reads are reads originated from repetitive regions of the genome hence they can be aligned to multiple positions. The ambiguity of multi-reads alignment renders them to be deleted wasting ~20% of the sequencing depth which can be translated into hundreds of millions of reads for one biological replicate. Through a hierarchical model that probabilistically allocates Hi-C multi-reads to their most likely genomic origins by utilizing specific characteristics of the paired-end reads of the Hi-C assay, the chromatin domain boundaries are refined and we can also detect novel promoter-enhancer interactions that involve disease-associated genes. Moreover, mHi-C, itself is programmed into a python pipeline with C acceleration, can process from raw data and output valid genomic interactions. Another urgent demand from both experimental labs and computational groups is a tool to fast simulate Hi-C contact matrices to work as biological replicates to improve the detection power or employed as a test of models under development. Also, the tool should be easy to use for researchers from all kinds of background. Therefore, I have developed FreeHiC (Zheng et al. 2020. &lt;strong&gt;Nature Methods&lt;/strong&gt;) and FreeHi-C SpikeIn (Zheng et al. 2021. &lt;strong&gt;Methods&lt;/strong&gt;)  which empirically learns the interacting fragment behaviors,  sequence characters, according to the Hi-C experimental protocol procedures. Sequently, with the user-controlled level of noise being inserted into the simulation process,  a similar Hi-C interaction matrix is generated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;















&lt;figure  &gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;te&#34; srcset=&#34;
               /project/3dgenome/proEnh_huef65e6b39926a46dde47da1501849d32_408863_a581e4855ed8ab71af002cca53f70826.webp 400w,
               /project/3dgenome/proEnh_huef65e6b39926a46dde47da1501849d32_408863_99ae51a052a135af039d1fbd809b937b.webp 760w,
               /project/3dgenome/proEnh_huef65e6b39926a46dde47da1501849d32_408863_1200x1200_fit_q100_h2_lanczos_3.webp 1200w&#34;
               src=&#34;https://yezhengSTAT.github.io/project/3dgenome/proEnh_huef65e6b39926a46dde47da1501849d32_408863_a581e4855ed8ab71af002cca53f70826.webp&#34;
               width=&#34;760&#34;
               height=&#34;447&#34;
               loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recently, single-cell high-throughput chromatin conformation capture methodologies (scHi-C) enable profiling long-range genomic interactions. However, data from these technologies are prone to technical noise and biases that hinder downstream analysis. Collaborating with Keles Lab, we developed a normalization approach, BandNorm, and a deep generative modeling framework, scVI-3D, to account for scHi-C specific biases. In benchmarking experiments, BandNorm yields leading performances in a time and memory efficient manner for cell-type separation, identification of interacting loci, and recovery of cell-type relationships, while scVI-3D exhibits advantages for rare cell types and under high sparsity scenarios. Application of BandNorm coupled with gene-associating domain analysis reveals scRNA-seq validated sub-cell type identification.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;















&lt;figure  &gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;te&#34; srcset=&#34;
               /project/3dgenome/bandnorm_hu2a9a438c7ab07ad6356b77f110c7929a_1231035_7d18f3aab3f3afbfe9e3da14b1ace5b5.webp 400w,
               /project/3dgenome/bandnorm_hu2a9a438c7ab07ad6356b77f110c7929a_1231035_3e3ea8a5fead5556505e7f925f86bf02.webp 760w,
               /project/3dgenome/bandnorm_hu2a9a438c7ab07ad6356b77f110c7929a_1231035_1200x1200_fit_q100_h2_lanczos_3.webp 1200w&#34;
               src=&#34;https://yezhengSTAT.github.io/project/3dgenome/bandnorm_hu2a9a438c7ab07ad6356b77f110c7929a_1231035_7d18f3aab3f3afbfe9e3da14b1ace5b5.webp&#34;
               width=&#34;760&#34;
               height=&#34;555&#34;
               loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;publication&#34;&gt;Publication&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Zheng Y+&lt;/strong&gt;, Shen S+, Keleş S. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1101/2021.03.10.434870&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Normalization and De-noising of Single-cell Hi-C Data with BandNorm and scVI-3D&lt;/a&gt;. bioRxiv. Under the second round of review by &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Genome Biology&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;. 2022. (+: co-first authors)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cheng J, Clayton J, Acemel R, &lt;strong&gt;Zheng Y&lt;/strong&gt;, Taylor R, Keleş S, Harley J, Quail E, Gómez-Skarmeta J and Ulgiati D. &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.frontiersin.org/articles/10.3389/fimmu.2022.901747/full&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Regulatory architecture of the RCA gene cluster captures an intragenic TAD boundary and enhancer elements in B cells&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Frontiers in Immunology, section B Cell Biology&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;. 2022.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Zheng Y&lt;/strong&gt;, Zhou P, Keleş S. &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/abs/pii/S1046202320300852?via%3Dihub&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;FreeHi-C Spike-in Simulations for Benchmarking Differential Chromatin Interaction Detection&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Methods&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;. 2021.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Huang K, Wu Y, Shin J, &lt;strong&gt;Zheng Y&lt;/strong&gt;, Siahpirani A, Lin Y, Ni Z, Chen J, You J, Keleş S, Wang D, Roy S, Lu Q. &lt;a href=&#34;https://journals.plos.org/plosgenetics/article?id=10.1371/journal.pgen.1009309&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Transcriptome-wide transmission disequilibrium analysis identifies novel risk genes for autism spectrum disorder&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;PLOS Genetics&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;. 2021.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Zheng Y&lt;/strong&gt;, Keleş S. &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.nature.com/articles/s41592-019-0624-3&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;FreeHi-C simulates high-fidelity Hi-C data for benchmarking and data augmentation&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Nature Methods&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;. 2020.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The ENCODE Project Consortium, et al. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1038/s41586-020-2493-4&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Expanded Encyclopedias of DNA Elements in the Human and Mouse Genomes&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Nature&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;. 2020 .&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The ENCODE Project Consortium, Snyder, M.P., Gingeras, T.R., Moore, J.E., Weng, Z., Gerstein, M.B., Ren, B., Hardison, R.C., Stamatoyannopoulos, J.A., Graveley, B.R., Feingold, E.A. and Pazin, M.J. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1038/s41586-020-2449-8&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Perspectives on ENCODE&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Nature&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;. 2020.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Zheng Y&lt;/strong&gt;, Ay F, Keleş S. &lt;a href=&#34;https://elifesciences.org/articles/38070&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Generative modeling of multi-mapping reads with mHi-C advances analysis of Hi-C studies&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;eLife&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;. 2019.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>scGAD: single-cell gene associating domain scores for exploratory analysis of scHi-C data</title>
      <link>https://yezhengSTAT.github.io/publication/scgad/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://yezhengSTAT.github.io/publication/scgad/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Normalization and De-noising of Single-cell Hi-C Data with BandNorm and scVI-3D</title>
      <link>https://yezhengSTAT.github.io/publication/bandnorm/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://yezhengSTAT.github.io/publication/bandnorm/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>FreeHi-C Spike-in Simulations for Benchmarking Differential Chromatin Interaction Detection</title>
      <link>https://yezhengSTAT.github.io/publication/freehicspikein/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://yezhengSTAT.github.io/publication/freehicspikein/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>FreeHi-C simulates high-fidelity Hi-C data for benchmarking and data augmentation</title>
      <link>https://yezhengSTAT.github.io/publication/freehic/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://yezhengSTAT.github.io/publication/freehic/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>FreeHi-C simulates high-fidelity Hi-C data for benchmarking and data augmentation</title>
      <link>https://yezhengSTAT.github.io/publication_old/freehic/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://yezhengSTAT.github.io/publication_old/freehic/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Three-dimensional genome architecture and disease variants</title>
      <link>https://yezhengSTAT.github.io/post/3dreview/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://yezhengSTAT.github.io/post/3dreview/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I feel lucky to run into &lt;a href=&#34;https://genomemedicine.biomedcentral.com/articles/10.1186/s13073-017-0477-2&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Three-dimensional genome architecture and emerging technologies: looping in disease&lt;/a&gt; on Twitter. This review comprehensively and logically discussed the hierarchical genome architecture and summarized existing three-dimensional genome structure techniques: &amp;ldquo;C&amp;rdquo;-related, CHiC, Capture-HiC, DNase-HiC, ChIA-PET/HiChIP/PLAC-seq and CRISPR-based methods, with a gigantic table, reviewing the advantages/limits/relevant examples/computational pipeline.
More importantly, it is such a resourceful paper that summarized how researchers associated all kinds of 3D techniques with disease-related SNPs. This gave us a clear view of what kind of 3D datasets publically available and to what extent have scientists come up with statistical models to link SNPs from non-coding regions with distal genes. I listed a few of them as follows:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;3D techniques, CHi-C/p-CHi-C/HiCap, provides high-resolution cis-interactome data at clinically relevant loci such as regulatory elements, single nucleotide polymorphisms (SNPs) from GWASs, TAD boundaries or promoters. Important tools for connecting GWAS outcomes to target genes (many loci to all loci). (Namely, they can extract &amp;ldquo;promoter - other regions&amp;rdquo; interactions.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pipeline to analyze them: &lt;a href=&#34;https://genomebiology.biomedcentral.com/articles/10.1186/s13059-016-0992-2&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;CHiCAGO: robust detection of DNA looping interactions in Capture Hi-C data.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Capture-Hi-C: A detailed catalogue of 22,000 promoter interactions was generated using promoter CHi-C for two blood cell types: the lymphoblast line GM12878 and CD34+ hematopoietic progenitor cells. 3D interaction data indicated that SNPs associated with autoimmune and other hematological disorders were significantly enriched at interacting distal regulatory sites of targeted promoters. &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.nature.com/articles/ng.3286&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Mapping long-range promoter contacts in human cells with high-resolution capture Hi-C.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;CHi-C was also applied to study autoimmune-disease associated SNPs in GM12878 B-cell and Jurkat T-cell lines. These findings demonstrated that different autoimmune-associated variants interact with common gene promoters. They also contradict the long-held assumption that disease-causing genes and their associated variants should be in close linkage disequilibrium (LD) to impart an effect. &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.nature.com/articles/ncomms10069&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Capture Hi-C reveals novel candidate genes and complex long-range interactions with related autoimmune risk loci.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;2&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;3D techniques, ChIA-PET/HiChIP/PLAC-seq, study protein-specific chromatin interactome. Important in identifying chromatin architectural roles for proteins (many loci to all loci). (Namely, they study the &amp;ldquo;protein binding sites - other regions&amp;rdquo; interactions. Protein binding sites are similarly studied by ChIP-seq.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;HiChIP identified genome-wide cohesin-mediated looping interactions: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.nature.com/articles/nmeth.3999&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;HiChIP: efficient and sensitive analysis of protein-directed genome architecture.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;PLAC-seq targets H3K4me3 histone marks to generate improved maps of promoter-enhancer interactions in mESCs: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.nature.com/articles/cr2016137&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Mapping of long-range chromatin interactions by proximity ligation-assisted ChIP-seq.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;3&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hi-C maps for cortical and germinal brain regions identified increased promoter-enhancer interactions compared with other tissues. The authors found novel human-gained enhancers showed significant overlap with lineage-specific lncRNAs and 108 significant schizophrenia-associated variants. (I feel it paper offers excellent data for a more advanced statistical model to link Hi-C with schizophrenia GWAS study!): &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.nature.com/articles/nature19847&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Chromosome conformation elucidates regulatory relationships in developing human brain.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Integrating study of 21 different cell and tissues types of Hi-C maps determines frequently interacting enhancer regions (FIRE) which usually associated with super-enhancers, typical enhancers etc (basically they are biologically functionally active regions).  FIREs are tissue-specific, distinct disease-associated FIREs further strengthens the association: Alzheimer&amp;rsquo;s SNPs were found in brain-specific FIREs and SNPs for acute lymphoblastic leukemia were found in GM12878-specific super-FIREs. &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S2211124716314814&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;A Compendium of Chromatin Contact Maps Reveals Spatially Active Regions in the Human Genome.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A MODEL leveraged existing Hi-C data to determine that variants at regulatory elements outside of LD blocks interacted with genes or their enhancers harboring linked SNPs to impact gene expression and disease risk: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.nature.com/articles/ng.3674&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Modeling disease risk through analysis of physical interactions between genetic variants within chromatin regulatory circuitry.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another study generates extensive catalogues of distal genomic regions that interact with promoters, or promoter-interacting regions (PIRs), in 17 primary hematopoietic cell types, linking 2500 novel SNPs to putative disease-associated genes related to blood and autoimmune disorders. &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0092867416313228?via%3Dihub&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Lineage-Specific Genome Architecture Links Enhancers and Non-coding Disease Variants to Target Gene Promoters.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is not in the review paper but certainly offers good Hi-C and other DNA sequencing datasets for Cardiac Myocytes: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ahajournals.org/doi/full/10.1161/CIRCULATIONAHA.117.029430&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;High Resolution Mapping of Chromatin Conformation in Cardiac Myocytes Reveals Structural Remodeling of the Epigenome in Heart Failure.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Collectively, this review paper is really a good starting point for establishing thoughts of modeling how distal non-coding regulatory variants impact gene using 3D technologies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;license&#34;&gt;License&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Copyright 2017-present Ye Zheng.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Released under the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/gcushen/hugo-academic/blob/master/LICENSE.md&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;MIT&lt;/a&gt; license.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
